

EDUCATION

PhD, Human Interface Technology

University of Oxford (UK), University of Canterbury (NZ)

01/2013 - 12/2016

 Thesis: The Power of Robot Groups with a Focus on Persuasive and Linguistic Cues

MSc, Media Informatics

Vienna Institute of Technology (AT), University of Copenhagen (DK)

01/2011 - 12/2012

BSc, Computer Science

Vienna Institute of Technology (AT)

01/2007 - 12/2011

Engineer, Electronic and Computer Science

HTBLA - Steyr (AT)

01/2001 - 12/2006

SKILLS

Tech

Cursor · Typescript · Next.js · React.js ·

AI SDK (Vercel) · LLMs (OpenAI/Azure) ·

PostgreSQL · Supabase · Firebase ·

Cloud-Functions · Material UI · GCP

Team

Product Management · Hiring ·

Mentoring & Leadership · Design Thinking

Business

Go to Market Strategy · Data Analytics ·

Board Advisor · Customer Experience · BI ·

OKRs

Languages

German · English · Arabic

JÜRGEN BRANDSTETTER

Al Engineer / CTO / Founding Engineer / Full-Stack Developer

SUMMARY

As an Al Engineer, Foundering Engineer, Full-Stack Developer, and CTO with more than 15 years of experience, I assist start-ups with their technical needs, in particular applied Al. This includes leadership, strategy, mentoring, architecture, code reviews, and of course, Al-coding. I'm especially adept at working with remote-first companies, having previously founded one and been responsible for developing its internal communication strategy.

EXPERIENCE

Al Engineering / Head of Engineering (Consultant)

10/2023 - Present

Self Employed

Remote (Linz, AT)

- Trained developers in Al-first development (Cursor, Background-Al), accelerating code generation, review, and debugging
- Designed an Agentic RAG based search system for the AEC industry, processing terabytes of highly complex construction drawing plan
- Established and led an Al/Tech team for an On-Demand Al-Clothing company, implementing systems and processes
- Utilized Vision-LLM system for efficient categorization of 20,000+ weekly emails, improving back-office operations
- Implemented internal tools using Re-Tool to enhance on-demand clothing manufacturing processes
- Created Al-Quality-Assurance tools to maintain high standards for LLM-generated content

CTO & Co-Founder

2016 - Present

Remote (Auckland, NZ)

amy.app | Al Maths-Tutoring Ed-Tech Start-up

• Scaled the company to ~25 members

- Built a globally distributed tech team spanning over 5 continents
- Reported to the board and CEO via board reports and analytics
- Managed and developed the enterprise, school and student facing products
- Responsible for the software architecture of all internal and external products
- Recruit, hire and mentor tech talent
- Implement product tracking (Mixpanel) to better understand the customers journey
- Implemented and managed the product monetization system (Stripe)
- Created a real-time, multi-user question editor with React to handle over 100k items
- Improved content compiler for real-time operation, cutting run time from 2 days

Visiting Researcher

06/2014 - 10/2014

Microsoft Research Fuse Labs

Manhattan, NYC, USA

- Used humanoid robots to persuade office workers to stand at least once per hour

 Diblished multiple scientific garages in LIDI.
- Published multiple scientific papers in HRI

Android & Web Developer

07/2012 - 02/2013 Vienna, Austria, EU

OpenResearch | App Development Agency

• Developed a product comparison android app (Geizhals)

• Developed a web based e-reader (Heute)

Android Developer

09/2010 - 02/2011

OpenResearch | App Development Agency

Vienna, Austria, EU

• Developed a gas comparison android app (ÖAMTC)

Developed google-maps marker cluster algorithms for android

Product Manager & Web Developer

04/2007 - 09/2007

A-K-D Wohnservice GmbH | Interior Design and Production

Linz, Austria, EU

$\bullet\,$ Developed the companies internal project and customer tracking system

• Developed the companies web-presence

CTO & Co-Founder

01/2004 - 12/2010 Linz, Austria, EU

WER ist IN | Online company register for maps

- Developed the web platform to show venue details
- Engaging customers and making sales at conference booths
- Door-to-door sales

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Self Employed

06/2003 - 12/2010 Linz, Austria, EU

- Auto generated 300 webpages for a customer during the summer holidays
 Developed my own PHP CMS
 Built the web-presence for local SMEs
 SEO